How's things?
Status quo.
Yeah?
Mm-hmm.
That's good.
What's going on, Em?
Yeah, it's good
to see you, Brendan.
It's been some time.
Two months.
Yeah, I didn't even know
your locker.
I had to ask Brain.
Em, why don't we meet
somewhere?
Mm, I can't.
Why not?
I screwed up real bad.
You know?
I really screwed up.
Screwed up how?
I-I did what she said
with the brick.
I-I didn't know
it was bad.
But put the Pin's on it
now for poor Frisco,
and they're playing it
all on me.
Slow down.
Now, what?
You gotta help me,
Brendan, please.
I think Tug--
Oh, no!
Brain.
Brendan, it's been a while.
Where you been eatin'?
- Back of school.
- Yeah, no one's seen you.
- What's it been,
a couple of months?
- It's been a while.
Did you gave Emily
my locker number?
- Few days ago.
Was I wrong?
- No.
It's been so long, I don't
know your two's stats.
Yeah,
it's been a while.
Who's she been
eating with?
I don't know.
That's hard to keep track.
- Is it?
- Can be.
Can be hard
to keep track
of those things,
because lunch
is, um, a lot of things.
Lunch is difficult.
She hadn't been doin'
too good, Brendan.
Yeah, well,
I'm not looking
for a patch-up.
Em's life is her own,
but she asked
for my help.
- Help with what?
- I don't know.
I don't even care.
It's not my business.
I just want to know
she's okay.
We gotta find her.
That's all this is.
I know she's been poking in
with the Ivy-bound
cheerleading elite.
- Laura Dannon's crowd.
- Laura Dannon there
on the Linc'?
And Brad Bramish,
cream on the upper crust.
Em tagged after them
for a bit, but it
didn't work out.
She picked her way
down the food chain.
Last I saw she was
with what's-her-name,
the drama vamp.
Small-time dealer,
evil one.
- The one you dated.
- Kara.
That's my bus.
You know her locker number?
Kara's?
Em's.
269.
Thanks, Brain.
Keep your specs on,
find me if she shows.
Will do.
Hello, Kara.
- Hello, Brendan.
- Kara.
- Come to see the show?
- No, I didn't.
Lapdog, blow.
Stay.
- I need words.
- Well, I'm listening.
About Emily Kostich.
Run and get my purse.
Go on. Hurry up.
Still picking your teeth
with freshmen?
- You were a freshman once.
- Way once, sister.
You and Em,
tight for a bit.
- Who's she eating with now?
- Eating with?
Eating with.
Lunch. Who?
You're a cutie.
Brendan.
I don't know
where she is.
I know you do,
so why don't you
want me to find out?
Well, maybe
I'm looking out for you.
Oh, I appreciate that.
Brendan.
If you're ever looking
to get back into things,
I could use you.
Go. Say your line, okay?
- No.
- So, I just--
No, he's gotta come in first
and then you say your line.
And then he crosses.
Hello?
Yes. Hello, ma'am,
this is Tom.
I'm a friend from school.
Could I speak to--
Oh sure, Tom.
Laura's here.
Just a sec.
Yes?
I'm calling for details.
For what?
Details about the party.
Who is this? Or I'll hang up.
- You don't know me.
I'll save you some time.
- I know everyone,
- and I have all the time
in the world.
- The folly of youth.
Ask whose invitation
I've got.
What you said.
Emily Kostich.
15 Busch Streetin Stockton Cove.
Buzz 42 at the gate. 9:00.
But who gave you--
And the stupid coach--
the coach won't let me play!
So, cheers!
Beautiful.
I am Brad Bramish, Coach!
You gotta let me play!
How am I supposed
to put in my best game...
if I'm worried
about whether or not...
I'm gonna be in there?
What are you doing here?
Leaving.
Oh, yeah?
Brad's not the kind of guy
you want to mess with.
Fearless Flyer.
Quit your yappin'
and fix me one.
Mm. I'll never get
through all this.
- So why are you here tonight?
- I'm looking for Emily.
Em's been AWOL
for a good month.
- Nobody's seen her.
- I saw her yesterday.
Nearly nobody.
Listen,
you're scratching
at the wrong door.
I didn't know Em well enough
to know the details of what
she was in,
I just got wind
of the downfall.
If you haven't got
a finger in Em's troubles,
then why did her name
get me into your rather
exclusive party?
Keep up with me now.
I don't know,
but it sounded
like you did.
And a body's got a right
to be curious.
- Now I'm not so sure.
- Oh, put that body to bed.
I don't know a damn thing
about whatever troubles...
and that works for me.
I just want
to find her.
Coffee and Pie.
Coffee and Pie,
Oh My?
And you didn't
hear it from me.
It's Tugger.
All right.
Will you wait here
for me?
Sure.
You'll sit right here
and wait?
I'll just be
five minutes.
Yes.
Okay.
- Why don't you say something?
- I will not talk about this.
We'll talk about
this right now!
I won't!
We'll talk
about this!
I promise you.
Where's Dode?
Hey, Brendan.
Maybe you shouldn't be here.
Kara told me
you know where Em's at.
Uh-huh.
And why you looking
for Em?
She asked for my help.
Uh-huh.
Well, listen, man,
I got plenty on my plate
without dealing with
some jilted ex.
It's not about that.
Whatever it's about,
act smarter than you look
and drop it.
Where's she at?
You better get
while it's good.
Heel it now, dig?
- Uh, yo--
- Throw one at me
if you want, hash-head!
I got all five senses
and I slept last night.
- That puts me six up
on the lot of you.
- Easy, bro.
Where's Em?
All right! All right.
All right.
All right, man.
Where's Em?
She's with me.
She was tight
when she called you, man.
Came to and freaked,
told me to shake you
if you came by.
Said you'd only
make things worse.
Deal with whatever
this ain't about and drop it!
Tell Em I want
to see her.
Tell her if she wants
my help or not,
it's her business.
But I want to hear it
straight from her.
She don't wanna--
Today! She knows
where I eat lunch.
And stay out, man!
I must've sounded
pretty crazy on the phone
yesterday.
You just gotta
forget about it.
That's how you can
help me out is just,
please,
forget about it.
Brendan,
I know that you're mad
at all these people...
because you think
I went away from you
and went to them,
but...
you gotta start
seeing it as my decision.
You know, stop getting angry
just because where
I wanna be at...
is different
from where you
wanna be at, okay?
Who fed you
that line, Em?
Stop picking on Dode, okay?
He's a good guy.
The pie house rat?
Yeah.
He's a good friend.
So what am I?
Yeah, I mean,
what are you, um,
eating back here,
hating everybody?
I mean, who are you
judging anyone?
God, I really
loved you a lot.
I couldn't stand it.
I had to get with people.
I couldn't heckle life
with you anymore.
I'm so sorry.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry,
Brendan.
I'm sorry.
You gotta
come back to me, Em.
No!
You're in a spot,
but I can get you out.
Come back to me.
You're not hearing me!
I don't wanna be put away
and protected.
I'll deal with--
No!
Tell me about the trouble
with the brick, the Pin.
Are you going to fix things
like you did with Jerr?
No. Okay?
I came here to say
good-bye, okay?
For good.
Whatever you have to do
to let me go,
you gotta do it.
You gotta
promise me though, okay?
You have to, that--
that you're not--
you're not gonna
torture yourself.
Please?
That you're just
gonna let me go.
Just let me go.
Do you know
anything else about this?
No.
Slim pickings.
Why'd you let Dode fly
when he went back to
who's-her-name in theater?
Kara?
It's their turf.
I couldn't hear 'em
without being seen, and that
would only biff their play.
Best to know it's there,
let it ride and see what
comes of it. Anyway.
If this is what I think
it is, it didn't come
straight from Dode.
Unless he's playing
out of his league.
- I could only give you
my best guess.
- Yeah.
When the upper crust
does shady deeds,
they do them
in different places
around town.
One of them
is by the pier.
Another is by
the bike trails
of state park.
There's a lot of 'em,
and the pitch is they've got
little symbols for each one...
so they can tell each other
the place without word
getting around.
- This might be that.
- But Dode wouldn't know it?
No, this is
the upper crust.
Dode's pie-pan grease.
- Call anything up?
- How many places
start with "A"?
Or if it's a shape,
could be a random symbol.
Even if you figure it out,
what good would you do?
You said her business
was none of yours.
So she's all right.
Forget it now.
Go home, sleep.
Brendan, you're up early.
Couldn't sleep.
Find Emily?
You all right?
Yeah. What are you
here for? Zero?
Forced into taking
the early bus.
The others don't run
by my street.
So what's the word
with Em?
She's gone.
Can't raise her?
No, I can't.
So what now?
Now, I don't know,
I guess, uh--
I don't know.
I can't let
her go, Brain.
I was set to,
but I can't.
I don't think I can.
Do you think
you can help her?
No.
You think you
can get this straight,
maybe break some
deserving teeth?
Yeah, I think I could.
Well?
Tell me to walk
from this, Brain.
Tell me to drop it.
Walk from it.
Drop it.
But you're thick,
Brendan.
Yes, I am.
I need you to op.
Like on Jerr,
but that was cake to this.
And unlike Jerr,
there's not much chance
coming out clean.
24-7 on this one.
You okay to op
for me again?
So what first,
tip the bulls?
No, bulls
would gum it.
They'd flash
their dusty standards
at the wide-eyes,
probably find
some yegg to pin,
probably even
the right one.
But they'd trample
the real tracks...
and scare
the real players
back into their holes.
If we're doing this
I want the whole story.
No cops,
not for a bit.
So what's first?
I don't know.
- Your mom still have
that cell?
- In her car.
May I borrow it
for a few days?
Get me the number?
- Yeah.
- Wait for my word.
And, um,
cover for me first.
I'm, uh, gonna be
a little late.
What did you do? Stop it!
What did you do? Are you crying for him?
You're crying for Jerr?
Trueman went
straight for him!
He knew the lay!
You ratted on Jerr!
Stop it now, Em!
Are you telling me it isn't true?
Look at me!
You ratted him out
because you were jealous.
No, I spun on him and bulled the two-bit toker...
'cause I know what his world would do to you!
I love you
too much to see that. You don't love me!
You just wanna keep me. You're the only thing I love!
You're the only thing I love. And this is how I do it.
I wanna keep you safe.
You can't keep me safe,
Brendan, all right?
I'm in
a different world now.
And you can't
keep me out of it
and you can't beat it,
not if I don't
want you to.
Here's the cell number.
Keep it on vibrate.
Yeah.
Better stop meeting me
in the open too.
I'm gonna start getting
visible. I need you
on the underneath.
I'll call.
Trueman the Ass V.P.
wants words.
I'll bet he does.
Keep him off me.
Stonewall him.
He won't bite.
Keep him away from me.
I'll try.
So what's first?
Make Em's troubles mine.
Emily said four words
I didn't know.
"Brick"?
- No.
- Or "bad brick"?
- "Tug"?
Tug. Tug might be a drink.
Like milk and vodka
or something.
"Poor Frisco"?
Frisco.
Frisco Farr was
a sophomore last year.
Real trash,
maybe hit a class a week.
Didn't know him then,
hadn't seen him around.
- "Pin."
- Pin.
- The Pin?
- The Pin, yeah?
The Pin's kind of
a local spook story.
- You know, the Kingpin.
- I've heard it.
Same thing.
Supposed to be old,
like 26, lives in town.
Dope runner, right?
Big time.
See, the Pin pipes it
from the lowest scrapper
to Brad Bramish himself.
Maybe. Ask any dope rat
where the junk sprang,
and they'll say
they scraped it off that...
who scored it off this,
who bought it off someone.
After four
or five connections, the list
always ends with the Pin.
But I betcha you
got every rat in town
together and said,
show your hands if
any of them actually
seen the Pin,
you'd get a crowd
of full pockets.
You think the Pin's
just a tale to take
whatever heat?
Hmm.
But what's first?
Show of hands.
Hello, Brendan, are you
here for the show?
No.
Well, then could you
go then, honey, 'cause
I have this headache.
Try smoking
like a chimney.
I've heard that helps.
Hey, isn't this
Dode's brand?
You don't know
Dode's brand.
Mm, I do now.
I'm gonna start
shaking things up.
Give me the story,
you might miss
the bite.
The story about what?
All right.
I don't wanna play games
if you've got a headache.
Get me if you
wanna spill it,
but I can't
guarantee safe passage
after tonight.
I don't know what--
Tell the Pin that Brad
was my calling card...
and I need words.
Brad Bramish?
Tail Kara at lunch.
She's got rehearsal,
but she'll blow early.
She goes home, drop her.
Else, wait for my call.
Will do.
I mean, am I crazy? Huh?
This is all
I am trying to say here!
Okay, if you put me
in the game,
Brad Bramish
is gonna do what needs
to be done, baby. Okay?
But they don't
put me in,
what needs doing
ain't gonna get done!
Huh? And then don't
come crying to me--
"Boo-hoo-hoo-hoo
hoo-hoo"--
if you don't put me
in the game!
Now am I right?
Of course I'm right!
And don't come to me
if you don't let me play!
- They didn't.
- Shut up!
What are you
doing here?
Just listening.
All right,
you got me.
I'm a scout
for the Gophers.
Been watching your game
for a month,
but that story right there
just clinched it!
You got heart, kid.
How soon can you be
in Minneapolis?
Yeah?
Cold winters, but they got
a great public transit system.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Oh, yeah?
There's a thesaurus
in the library.
"Yeah" is under "Y."
Go ahead. I'll wait.
Yo, who invited you?
To the parking lot?
Gee, I guess
I invited myself.
Maybe you wanna go
somewhere more private.
With you?
Mm.
Sure.
This boy knows
what's good for him,
he'll just beat it.
Whoopin' this small fry's butt
ain't gonna help me none.
Sure ain't gonna
help him neither.
Come on, Brad!
Hey, is there a fight?
Yeah.
You're quite a pill.
Uh-huh.
Where are you going?
Home.
Why did you
take a powder
the other night?
Same reason
I'm taking one now.
Hold it.
I want to help you.
Go away!
Look,
I can't trust you.
You ought to be smart
enough to know that.
I didn't shake up the party
to get your attention, and I'm
not heeling you to hook you.
Your connections
could help me,
but the bad baggage
they bring would make it
zero-sum gain or even hurt me.
Better off coming
at it clean.
I wouldn't have to
lead you in by the hand.
I... can't...
trust... you.
Brad was a sap.
You weren't.
You're with him,
so you're playing him.
So you're a player.
With you behind me,
I'd have to tie one eye up
watching both of your hands.
I can't spare it.
You're not Brad.
No, I'm not.
You didn't call.
Sorry.
Kara went home though,
didn't she?
Yeah, but she stopped at a pay phone and made two calls...
that she didn't want
on her phone bill.
Get the numbers?
No, sorry.
It's all right.
Me and Brad
front page news?
All the buzz.
You really do them?
Yeah.
Why, is Brad the Pin?
Brad? He's a sap!
I downed him on his field
and his crew didn't bite.
Now I know he's a sap,
and anyone who acts like
he isn't is profiting by it.
That's not why
I roughed him though.
For kicks?
Economics.
Brad's the school's
biggest Jake buyer,
so if this Pin is
behind all the selling,
I got his attention.
Anyway, now we've shaken
the tree. Let's wait and see
what falls on our heads.
Will do.
So you didn't
know this boy?
No, sir. Never seen him.
Hmm. And he just
hit you?
Like I said, he asked
for my lunch money first.
Good thing
I brown-bagged it.
Okay, Brendan,
I've been looking
to talk to you.
You've helped
this office out before.
No, I gave you Jerr
to see him eaten,
not to see you fed.
Fine.
Very well put.
Accelerated English.
Mrs. Kasprzyk.
- Tough teacher.
- Tough but fair.
Okay.
We know you're clean.
And you've--
Despite your motives,
you've always been
an asset to this office.
And you're a good kid.
I want to run
some names past you.
Hold it.
We're not done here.
I was done here
three months ago.
I told you then I'd give
you Jerr and that was that.
- I'm not your inside line
and I'm not your boy.
- That's not very helpful.
You know what I'm in
if the wrong yegg saw me
pulled in here?
- What are you in?
- No.
And no more of these
informal chats either.
You got a discipline issue
with me, write me up
or suspend me...
and I'll see you
at the parent conference.
Hold on!
I could write you up
for talking back to a V.P....
and for looking at me
in that threatening way.
I would exercise
a little tact, Mr. Frye.
You can't pull
a stunt like that...
unless there's something
I need you for.
So is there?
- Maybe.
Maybe there's something
you need from me.
Maybe.
All right, I need you
off my back completely
for the next few weeks.
There might be
some heat soon.
If it's something
I can't cover, I won't
go to bat for you.
If I get caught like that,
it's curtains anyway.
I can't have brass
cutting me favors in public.
I'm just letting
you know now...
so you don't come
kicking in my homeroom door
once trouble starts.
Okay.
Okay, here's
what I can do.
I won't pin you
for anything you
aren't caught at.
But if anything comes up
with your prints on it,
I can't help you.
Also, if I get
to the bottom
of whatever this is...
and it gets too hot,
and you don't deliver,
Veep's gonna need
someone to turn over,
police-wise.
And I'll have you.
So there better be
some meat at the end of this
like you say.
Or at least
a fall guy.
Or you're it.
Nope, Dode is M.I.A.
I'm nine of 10 that Kara's
got him, but who knows where?
I shook but she's
not spilling.
No more job offers,
so she's gotta play.
I know enough about Kara
to let that worry me.
All right, keep your specs
on for him. Any other news?
Some. Laura Dannon
came to me looking
for you.
She did, huh?
Fourth period.
Nearly shook me
upside down.
Can't say I didn't enjoy it, but why'd she come to me?
She's tapping Kara,
and Kara knows you know me. Well, she's some piece of work.
If I had known
where you were,
I might have told her.
That's the spirit.
Ask around for Dode,
tail Kara again at lunch.
I've got knives in my eyes.
I'm going home sick.
Call you tonight.
All right.
I want
to see the Pin.
I guess you do.
You the Pin?
Yeah.
So now I'm very, very curious
what you're gonna say next.
Maybe I'll just sit here
and bleed at you.
Hell, if you're
gonna go breaking
my best clients' noses...
and expect me
to play sandbag.
Anyway, you've been
sniffing me out
before then.
Sniffing for me
like a vampire bat...
for a horse
with a nick on its ear
that he can suck on.
They do that.
So now you got Tugger
to bring you in,
which he never does.
And you got me
listening.
So I'm very curious
what you have to say...
that better be
really, really good.
Why don't you call Ms. Dannon
in from the hall first.
She oughta hear this.
No dice, soldier.
Would have been
a neat trick though.
I was just gonna come up
with some bit of information...
or set up some phony deal,
anything so you'd let me walk.
Then I was gonna go
to the vice principal...
and spill him the street address
of the biggest dope port
in the burg.
- He knows zippo.
- 1250 Vista Blanca.
The ink blotter
on the desk, in the den
in the basement...
of the house
with the tacky mailbox.
You gonna do what now?
No good, soldier.
All right, Tug,
enough.
- Tug!
- Tug, stop!
My glasses?
To hell with you then.
Which wall is the door in?
Sorry about this, kid.
But what the hell
with what you said before?
Where you were at,
with all of us
and Tug a fist away,
you gotta use
your nut.
Allay the situation.
So yeah, you're not
scared of me,
I got it.
But I'm also thinking
you're a little nuts now,
so you've got that trade-off
with your situation.
But nuts isn't all bad.
So maybe it was
a good play.
I don't know.
So Laura
talked me down.
Why don't we
take you upstairs,
back with the living.
I thought we had
orange juice, Brendan.
I'm sorry.
How about some Tang?
No, that's more
like soda, isn't it?
Water's fine, ma'am,
thanks.
Oh, wait a minute.
We have apple juice here
if you'd like that.
Or we've got milk,
but you're having that
on your corn flakes.
Apple juice sounds terrific.
It's country style.
- That's perfect.
- And I'll even give it to you
in a little country glass.
How 'bout that?
Boys?
I'm fine Mrs. M.
Thanks, Mom.
Mmm.
Okay, well,
I'm gonna go, uh,
do something
in the other room.
So, how 'bouts we
take another snap
at hearing your tale?
I don't know.
It starts out
same as before,
and this floor
ain't carpeted.
- We're cooled off.
- Your muscle seemed
plenty cool...
putting his fist
in my head.
I want him out.
Lookee, soldier--
- The ape blows or I clam.
- So clam!
What have you got
I can't beat out of you
back in the basement?
Give us
a few minutes, Tug.
I'll call you
if whatever.
So?
About a year ago, I had
a small-time dealing partnership
with Jerr Madison.
- Know him?
- Till he took
the fall for you.
Yeah, well,
I didn't ask him to,
but he was a straight player,
and I got out clean, almost.
Nothing on my official record,
but the V.P.'s play it
like I owe 'em one.
When I made it clear
I wasn't gonna be playing
their hound dog,
well, they didn't
like it.
They keep badgering me
and calling me in.
Gee, that's tough.
I don't like being told
whose side I'm on.
So now they think
I'm on your trail.
I'm in a nice spot
to know their movements,
feed them yours.
- I got you.
- You haven't got me yet.
What, price?
Considering the benefits
my services could yield,
I don't think
that's unreasonable.
And what are
your services exactly?
So I can be specific
on the invoice.
Whatever serves
your interests.
Fair enough.
I'll have my boys
check your tale.
And seeing how it
stretches,
we'll either rub
or hire you.
You'll know which
by the end of the day
tomorrow.
We're done.
I'll drive you back.
Just drop me
at school.
How long was I out?
Half an hour.
Took all of it for me
to cool the Pin down.
Thanks.
Do you trust me now?
Less now than when I
didn't trust you before.
Maybe if you can tell me
your angle in all this
I could.
Emily tried to get
with Brad and I about--
Three months ago,
and you stonewalled her.
Oh, all right,
if you've already got
the world's address.
Three months ago.
And I liked her.
But she wasn't us
and it didn't work.
And when she left,
she took some
souvenirs with her,
dirty habits she wasn't
strong enough to control...
and a connection
to the Pin
to keep them going.
A few months pass,
and the next I hear
the Pin's raging...
over a certain situation
with the junk
Em's partial to.
And it's all coming down
on her head.
You're saying Em
scraped the junk off the Pin?
I don't care how hard
she was hooked,
I don't buy that.
You weren't there.
She wasn't herself.
It had dug deep.
It was awful.
Whether she scraped
or copped...
or just ran her tab
around the world
and into her own back,
must've been grand.
Never seen
the Pin so hot.
And when he thought
his precious--
his bricks of
whatever it was, when
one of them was missing...
he scared me.
Why are you
telling me all this?
What's your play?
You think
nobody sees you.
Eating lunch
behind the portables,
loving some girl
like she's all there is,
anywhere, to you.
I always seen you.
Or maybe
I liked Emily.
Maybe I see what you're
trying to do for her.
Trying to help her.
And I don't know anybody
who would do that for me.
Now you are dangerous.
Mr. Shanlan, should I
actually kiss her here?
No, no, just move on
to the next scene.
Brendan, Brendan, Brendan.
Where's Dode flopped?
I know you two
are cozed up,
so you tell me
or you won't.
Now, last time
I checked...
you were giving me
ultimatums.
It worked.
You went to Laura,
told her my tale.
- Part of the plan?
- Turned out to be.
I just feel
so cheap and used.
Gol, I must seem
a real cad.
Sometimes
I just hate myself.
Whatever happened
to us, Brendan?
Where's Dode flopped?
We used to be
a pair and a half.
Sometimes I miss having
someone to talk to.
Do you ever miss
having someone
to talk to?
Oh, yeah.
You must.
I need to hear Dode's tale
about Emily. It's important.
You better be sure
you wanna know
what you wanna know.
Laura's working
with me now,
and I'll have the Pin
and Tug in my corner soon.
The sooner I get the truth
from Dode or the truth
about Dode from you,
- the safer
you'll both be.
- Hmm.
No?
Then pass it on
to Dode anyway.
Maybe he'll have the sense
to get out from under you
before he gets hurt.
You didn't.
Did you?
Dode and Kara are shacked up, but what's their play?
I don't know.
Dode passed Emily the note.
He knows something.
Now Kara's got him
under her thumb,
she's gonna use him somehow.
But I don't know
and I don't know,
so all we can do is wait
till she shows some cards.
Anyway, tomorrow we see
if the Pin hires me
or breaks my knees.
Give us 70-30.
If we're in,
I get under his skin
and see what's what.
You stick to Kara,
keep your specs
peeled for Dode.
And stay away
from Laura.
I think she's
with us, Brendan.
I'll let you know when she is.
Okay.
You the Pin's?
What's his answer?
Push 'em back!
Push 'em back! Way back!
Way back!
Chuck Burns.
Long-haired lug,
deals, shines a blade.
I know him, I just can't
pin him to any crowd.
He's definitely not
muscle for anyone.
He taps the Carrow's crowd, but doesn't hang with them.
- If you've got a guess,
I could check it out.
- He's with the Pin.
Everything's kablooey,
and I gotta blow the burg.
I'll check it out and--
Never mind.
If I don't call by 3:00,
call in the bulls.
So?
So.
That's what you'll get
every week for your services.
Unless of course there's
some specific job,
in which you'll get
sliced in with my crew.
- Square?
- Yeah.
We're doing a thing
tonight down at The Hole.
Know it?
South of
T Street. Yeah.
It's a little
"welcome-you-in" thing.
6:00.
I know what you did.
I was in the tunnel.
I saw you hide her.
- Dode.
- Anyone I tell, it would ruin you some way,
and I'm gonna
tell someone.
Are you making an offer?
Maybe.
Or maybe
I'll just do you in.
Hire another hash-head
to blade me?
Don't need
no blade, shamus.
- I just gotta squawk.
- What do you want?
Just to see you sweat.
Brendan?
Brain.
Are you all right?
So I'm gonna start you
on the dope circles.
Anyway, there's
not much else doing.
I'm tailing out
this big deal,
but it's almost done.
Oh, yeah,
what was it?
It was big-time.
Biggest I ever done.
And there was a snag
in it, but it's
almost done now.
What was it?
You're going
to make me curious
being so curious.
I wanna lay
something out.
You're coming into
a certain situation,
and I'm sort of
bringing you in
because of it.
I didn't tell Tug
to hit you for
the Brad Bramish thing.
He got hot and
he just hit you.
He's been doing that.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Muscle you can't
control's no good
at that.
You're working for me,
not for Tug. That's all.
All right.
It's tough sometimes.
It's twisted, complicated.
I don't know.
Everyone's got
their thing.
You read Tolkien?
What?
You know,
the Hobbit books?
Yeah.
His descriptions
of things
are really good.
Oh, yeah,
he makes you want
to be there.
Don't go to class.
What?
Fifth period,
Trueman and the V.P.
come in asking for you.
Did they call your mom?
Probably.
I got in late.
Get out
of there too, then.
Meet me behind the library. I've got stuff.
Frisco Farr was
found on a sidewalk...
three weeks ago outside
of Pinkerton's Deli.
He was in a coma.
His stomach contained
a sausage sandwich,
a horse dose
of heroin and traces
of choleric tricemate,
which is a poisonous chemical
found in laundry detergent.
He's still under,
nobody's talking,
- so nothing's
come of it.
- O.D.?
No. The chem the junk
must've been cut with
put him down.
Bad junk, "bad brick."
Could that form of heroin
be called "brick"?
It was
a concentrated powder.
Its street handle
is "whip," "rock"
or "Brock."
From Laura.
I told you
to stay clear
of Laura.
- You tell her
to stay clear of me?
- I gotta get voice mail.
No, tell her I'll be
at the Pin's at 1:00.
Any news
with the lug?
No, no news.
This isn't good.
No.
Ask.
Administration.
Gary Trueman's office,
please.
This is Trueman.
What the hell are you doing
asking for me in class?
What the hell are you
doing out of class?
What?
The V.P. and I...
needed to ask you
a few questions
about Emily Kostich,
who you might
have heard is missing.
It's a very serious thing. The police are involved.
The V.P. and I knew
you two were close.
So the V.P. and I came
to ask you questions,
but you were truant--
- What?
- Been cut loose.
Not safe here.
We shouldn't have met
in the open. Lay low, but ask
on the underneath for Dode.
He set up
whatever Emily
walked into.
It's getting
more urgent
that we talk.
- What are you gonna do?
- I'd have liked
to play it safe,
but there's no time.
The Pin's not
letting anything drop.
Have to
push things a bit.
How?
- I don't know.
- Find Dode.
What with the poking, genius?
Maybe you're poking
for your bull friends?
I can't face up at school,
the V.P.'s so hot for me!
Maybe you're looking
to make good!
I'm looking to find
this big game
the Pin's played.
Not to gum it,
but just so when its tail
jams in my back,
I know who to bill
for the embalming!
- You ought to ask him
what you wanna know.
- I did. He didn't tell me.
The Pin's not
giving me the straight.
That makes me nervous.
Makes me angry.
Yeah.
That's understandable.
There was 10 of them.
I don't know
where he picked them,
he didn't tell me.
Huh.
So we get
10 kilos of Brock.
Ain't enough marks
in the whole burg
to eat that,
so he unloads eight up north,
even up to the docks.
I don't know who.
- Didn't tell you.
- Yeah.
That was eight.
So that's the tenth
in there.
We gotta break it off
into doses.
Sell off around the high,
maybe some by Shorecliffs.
What about
the ninth brick?
Yeah, there were
some problems with that.
Oh, yeah?
It, uh--
It, uh, disappeared.
Someone skimmed it.
We started raising hell
with all the likely suspects,
and what do you know,
it came back.
But it came back bad.
One of ours took
a dose off the top,
laid him out.
Frisco?
Yeah, poor Frisco.
You heard about that?
We'll catch the rat.
Just takes time.
I heard something fell
with Emily Kostich.
Emily who?
Kostich?
Don't know her.
Has the Pin talked about her?
Not to me.
He might know something.
Ask him.
Tell me what he says,
'cause...
you know,
if he heard something,
I wanna check.
Sure.
Powwowing?
Just shootin' the shat.
Yeah, just shootin' it.
Good.
Tug, I got a call...
from someone who says
they know something
about Emily.
Emily?
Emily Kostich.
Where she's at now.
Says we'd wanna know.
Wants to meet.
Yeah?
So we'll meet.
4:00.
Emily used to be
Tug's girl.
You knew Emily,
didn't you?
A while back.
You've heard
she's missing?
I heard that.
So maybe you wanna
come along too.
What does Emily
got to do with you?
Show. Maybe we'll
find out.
4:00.
That's my ride.
Pay phone,
anywhere.
The mobile customer you've called is not available.
What time is it?
Brendan, you probably--
3:40!
You're exhausted.
You've swallowed
a lot of blood.
Get back
in the car.
Shut up!
You need to go to the
hospital. You're sick!
Shut up, please! Please!
Okay, what you gotta do
is drive around
in the pie house lot...
so Dode's gotta go by
you or me to get down
to the tunnel.
If you see Dode,
then honk four times,
long-short, long-short.
And don't be seen.
Get back in the car.
Do it!
Please?
I need you to do this.
I need you here.
Please.
- What are you doing, Dode?
- You gonna stop me?
- What do you think
you're doing?
- I saw what you did.
- What did you see?
- I saw you.
- Where?
- I was in the tunnel!
I saw you!
You were with her dead,
and you took the body!
I saw you hide it!
Yeah, I did.
That's all you saw?
What about before?
- Before what?
- Before I got there.
- Did you see
who killed her?
- You killed her!
- I found the body, Dode.
- No, you-- We--
I thought you didn't.
But we figured you out.
I got the news on you
'cause you hid the body.
- Who's we?
- Shut up! Shut up!
You're always talkin',
always this and that!
You're gonna shut up!
- I didn't kill her.
- You're not gonna talk!
- I know you're thinking of Em.
- Shut up!
I know you tried to help her.
You're gonna
shut your mouth!
Me and Kara,
we're gonna bury you,
and we're gonna get
paid doing it, dig?
You're gonna put it over
real nice!
You're in over your head.
You don't wanna put
your hand in this!
She's dead, you--
Why was she scared?
She came to me!
Who was she scared of?
I think I know why.
I just gotta know who!
You're trying to confuse me!
You couldn't stand it!
Your little Em!
She was gonna keep it.
It was mine,
and you couldn't stand that!
What was yours?
- I had you pegged.
- What was yours?
I loved her...
and I would have
loved that kid.
I'm gonna bury you.
What'd I miss?
Dode here says
Emily Kostich is dead.
Oh, yeah?
He says he knows
who did it.
Says he knows where the body is.
Says he wants
more money than I think
the information is worth.
That so,
Dode?
So walk.
What's the info have
to do with you anyways?
- Plenty.
- "Plenty," he says.
Uh-huh. And he wants cash
on the nail.
He's a pot-skulled
reef-worm with more hop
in his head than blood.
- Why pay for dirt
you can't believe?
- No, you'll believe this.
Maybe you will.
No, you will.
'Cause it's someone
close to you, real close.
Maybe it's hot,
but it's Dode.
- You can't trust it.
- Real close.
I'm getting
my shoes wet for this?
- Let him milk you if you want.
- - Stay.
It's still too much.
No, it isn't.
You won't complain
when you hear it.
- Maybe you should--
- You had her up against
the wall with the brick.
I know my business.
It's still too much.
No, it isn't 'cause
that's not why she was killed.
But it's real
important to you,
'cause the person
who killed her is real close,
'cause he's got a lot to lose.
And he knows if I don't bury him
by spilling to you,
I spill to the bulls
and I bury him for real.
And he's really,
really scared.
She had a kid in her,
and he couldn't stand it!
- Tug, it's all right!
- Tug, stop!
Tug!
Tug.
She sprung it
on me just--
It's a hell of a thing
to spring on a guy.
I don't remember much.
Laura talked me
down after.
Said whatever--
She knew her,
said it wasn't true.
But I still
think sometimes--
I think...
about it being true.
About it being mine.
Maybe I did it...
'cause I thought
it was true.
It's a hell of a thing.
You up?
What's the stats?
Everyone's just laying low.
You're here with us now
at my folks' place.
Everyone's
assuming it's war.
No one's said
anything yet.
Everyone's laying low.
At war?
- You're with us.
- The hell I am.
All right,
I'm with you.
Just lie low.
Sleep some more.
Laura, she said
you should sleep.
Stupid? Hey, Huxley,
I'm back!
Brendan?
Yeah.
Are you-- What? Man, have you heard about Dode?
I was there.
Where were you yesterday?
I called.
Kasprzyk took my phone, turned it off.
I just now got it back.
All right, listen.
Are you okay?
Just listen.
Is my name in the papers
with the story? No.
Is it just Dode's name
in the papers? Yeah. What do you mean?
Listen, I'm gonna be
calling you tonight,
probably late.
Sleep with your phone on.
Could you get a car
if you needed to?
If it's late enough, I could take my mom's.
Be ready then.
I'll call.
Brendan, did you hear
about Dode?
You scheming tramp.
You set that poor kid up.
You held Dode like a card
till you could play him.
For money!
I don't know what
you're talking about.
You'd bury me at the same time,
but it was mostly for the money!
You got Dode thinking Em
had his kid, thinking I did it,
and that was enough for him.
But he stuck to the money
'cause you had your claws
in him!
'Cause he couldn't
come away from the deal
without it and make you happy!
Brendan, I think you need
to sit down for a second.
I think you're just
a mess right now.
Can you please, sweetheart,
can you go run and get
my shoes from the locker room?
Still wish you knew
what you wanted to know?
You know, if it's any
consolation, it probably
wasn't Dode's kid.
It might have been Tug's kid.
Frankly, I wouldn't bet a horse.
It was kind of a crowded field
there at the end,
if you know what I mean.
Meanie.
Aaah!
What are you doing?
Showing your ace!
Far enough.
Everyone's paying
social calls.
So, what are
the stats?
- The stats are war.
- Tug got hot.
He panicked.
- Tug's been after my digs
from the get-go.
- No, he's been anxious.
He thought if you found out
he killed Emily,
you'd turn him over.
- He was right.
- Yeah, well.
I told him to get
the straight, no roughing.
I wasn't even there.
All right,
so he's a hothead.
You don't want him on your side.
Let's have a powwow before
we start digging trenches.
Maybe we can all walk away
amiable enemies.
Yeah, all right.
- 4:00.
- Tomorrow?
Tonight. Let's clear it all
before it boils up again.
Wait.
I'll drive you back.
So here's the sit.
You and the Pin
are gonna powwow tonight.
4:00, his place.
Bring all
the muscle you want,
you won't need it.
He wants to talk straight,
and you're gonna work with him
for whatever he needs.
- You don't want war.
- The hell I don't.
The Pin's sitting
on the brick profits.
Hitting him now would be post.
Make peace,
wait for your chance.
He's right, Tug.
Smooth it out.
Besides, he's got you
on the Dode thing.
War will mean you versus him
and every bull in the burg.
Yeah, we'll talk.
You going?
Yeah.
Go away.
I'm sorry,
Brendan.
I'm so sorry.
Don't go tonight.
I gotta
make sure everything
plays out smooth.
It'll play out
however it plays
without you there.
I gotta make sure.
Why?
'Cause if there's war,
I'm in it too.
I'm just scared.
If things go bad tonight,
just be careful.
- Your folks left
the car here?
- Yeah.
Take it and Laura's.
I'll go first in yours.
- The hell you'll take mine.
- The scenic route,
draw off any tailers.
They'll think it's you,
might even radio back
you're alone.
Mr. Smarts.
You got a cigarette?
I don't smoke.
I've seen you smoke.
I don't smoke
cigarettes.
Give me 15 minutes,
then go.
Write this down.
I'm gonna be out
of the Pin's by 4:15.
So at exactly 4:15,
you put an anonymous call in
to the bulls.
You tell them
there are drugs in the trunk
of the black Mustang...
outside the Pin's house.
- Can you get the car?
- Yeah.
All right,
after you call the cops,
go to Tug's house.
12 Elm.
Park outside and wait.
Laura's inside.
She hasn't got a car,
but if she blows on foot
or gets a pick,
tail her, all right?
All right?
Okay.
I'll call you
when it gets light.
Thanks, Brain.
Talk.
I want full assurance
that any heat from Emily
and Dode is on just you.
I don't even want my name
pulled into this shindig.
Second,
you owe me six C's.
No rush, but I want your shake
that they'll be home
in not too much time.
That's square.
You did him after all.
Lay low,
it'll blow over.
Stick on this, one of you
will dish it to bury the other,
you'll both get the rap.
As for the six,
did you borrow it?
- Yeah.
- Then you owe it. Shouldn't
need to shake on that.
All right to both.
Good. Let's seal it up
and blow for keeps.
Third thing.
The last brick.
It's yours.
That's not the point.
I'm gonna start
selling it.
How do I know
it's not bad?
- Why would it be?
- Why was the last one?
Because someone got greedy.
Tug here's had the means
to swipe half of it...
and cut it bad
for a long time.
Now we're splits.
The loss of my trust
is retroactive.
Did you, Tug?
No.
- All right,
let's shake and blow.
- Not good enough.
What would be
good enough?
I want to see him dose it...
just to prove it.
- Then we're square.
- Hell for that.
I didn't touch
your junk!
- That's all!
- I wanna see it.
- To hell!
- Your not wanting
to dose it...
- is proving something
to me right here.
- Oh, it better be.
It's tellin' that I ain't
under your thumb no more!
That I ain't playin' lapdog
to no Gothed-up cripple!
- I'll dose it.
- What?
If it will shut
you two apes up,
I'll take the dose.
If I don't die,
we're all right as rain.
Deal?
Fine.
Tangles.
Johnny,
go with him.
Where is it? Where's the brick?
What's happening?
- What'd you do with it?
- I didn't touch your brick!
You better give it back.
What's happening?
Cops?
No.
The brick--
The brick is gone.
Make peace, huh?
Talk it out?
Get your boys in my den
so you could snag it
under my nose!
No, all right?
It's not that!
Was it bad, Tug?
Snag it so I don't know,
or sell it off to flat
the war odds!
Pin, think about it!
I did all of that!
Tug, no!
Brendan!
No!
Help me! Uh!
No! No!
Brendan, please!
Stop!
Please, help me!
It's the cops!
- Cops!
- Help me!
Brendan, please!
Please!
- Hey, where are you?
- Library. Where are you?
Did she blow last night?
No, stayed there till 6:30,
then walked to school.
You didn't give her
a ride, did you?
No.
She came to school
straight from Tug's?
Yeah.
She there now?
Yeah. Not with me,
but here.
All right, tell her
I want to meet up on the
field in half an hour.
Then go home,
get some sleep.
Will do.
Did you see it all?
With the Pin and Tug?
No, I took your advice
and didn't go.
No?
What happened?
The papers say six dead.
Three around the house,
girl in the back of Tug's car,
and the Pin and Tug.
Yeah?
Tug tried
to shoot his way out
when the police got there.
They tied him to Dode too.
Same gun.
And the girl.
It's a good thing
you weren't there.
Yeah.
Do you think
the girl is Emily?
Probably.
You loved her?
Yeah, I did.
You did all of this
because you loved her.
And now it's finished.
No.
What?
It's not finished.
Tug pulled
the trigger on Em,
and he got the fall for it,
but the bulls could have
found that out without me.
I set out to know
who put her in the spot,
who put her
in front of the gun.
That was you, angel.
What are you talking about?
It was you.
- Brendan.
- What?
You want the whole tale?
You want me to tell it to you?
Tell it to me.
All right,
from the top.
You had your fingers
in Brad Bramish
for appearances...
and to keep him
buying from the Pin,
who you were hooked with.
When Emily came
to you and Brad,
you saw her
for what she was,
an insecure little girl
trying to get in.
She goes on
the back burner.
Meanwhile,
maybe you're getting bored,
maybe just greedy,
but when the Pin scores
big with the bricks,
you take your shot.
You hook one, take half,
cut it back to size,
but you cut it back bad.
Maybe accidentally, maybe to
down the Pin's operation,
doesn't matter.
You put it back.
Poor Frisco doses off it
and lands in a coma.
So now the Pin's fuming.
Maybe he's jealous of Brad,
so he comes to Brad's crowd
looking for blood,
or at least a scape'.
You're in big trouble.
There's gonna be
a war over this.
And there's Emily.
She trusts you.
She wants in.
- It's duck soup.
- No!
You frame her
for the bad brick,
then you cut her loose.
You turn on your heel
and bite her in the throat!
Last week at the pay phone,
Del Rio and Sarmentoso,
she saw something
she was scared of.
Tug's car driving by,
the Pin riding shotgun.
But she wouldn't
have seen the Pin.
No, she was across
the street, angel.
She saw the driver's side.
She saw you.
She saw you
and she ran like
she saw some devil.
Brendan, she was--
She took the hit.
Dode hid her away,
but the Pin was onto her.
He tracked her down
and told her to meet,
that they'd make good.
He gave her a time
and a place and sent Tug
to get the straight.
But maybe you had
talked Tug up.
Or maybe
he just blew a fuse.
But when Em sprung it
on him she had her kid,
he did what anyone
could count on
Tug doing:
He hit her.
She took the hit for you,
and you let her take it.
- Stop! Stop it!
- That's the tale.
- Tell me it's not.
- Stop it! No!
- Then tell me it's not.
- It's not.
It isn't true.
I hope it isn't.
I want you to have been
on my side all along.
Not just trying to get me
under your thumb...
like Brad,
and the Pin and Tug.
But I think you knew
that party was gonna
blow up.
I think that was
your final play.
But I hope I'm wrong.
I hope everything
I wrote in the note...
that I dropped
at Gary Trueman's office
this morning is wrong,
about your
and Brad's involvement
in the Pin's runnings.
And I hope you didn't steal
the brick last night...
in your purse.
I didn't.
Good.
That means you
didn't let me walk
into a slaughterhouse.
And you didn't lead the Pin
and Tug and their crews
to the slaughter.
And when Trueman
reads my note,
takes my cue and
searches your locker,
he won't find
a damn thing.
Oh, Brendan,
don't do this.
It's done.
Done?
Well, that's most of it.
Nine out of 10.
I told Em
to tell Tug it was his.
Told her it would
soften him up.
Sh-- She said she wished
she could keep it,
but she didn't love
the father.
I was gonna drive her
down to the doctor
the next day.
Most wouldn't.
She was already
starting to show.
Three months.
Do you know whose kid
that makes it?
Or have you known
all along?
Mother--
You get your straight?
Yeah.
I wouldn't have,
if I, uh--
It's all right.
Chuck Burns came to.
Knife guy.
Spilled it all to the bulls.
Turns out Brad Bramish
hired him on his own.
It was just
a grudge thing.
Fits.
You did good, Brain.
Go sleep.
Yeah, you too.
What'd she
whisper to you?
She called me
a dirty word.
All right,
you don't have
to tell me.