I sent you 20 letters
from Paris last year.
Well, you've been gone six months.
And I got the fear.
After all the songs
that we've sung together.
After all the sweet
and all the stormy...
if I knew where you were.
Well, I would surely inform you that...
But every night don't you.
Sleep on your right?
Don't you...
Hey, Ash, where are we?
Well, we just crossed
the Tennessee border.
- Which would put us...
- Yeah?
Which would put us...
right...
here.
Turn!
What the hell was that?
Are you trying to kill us?
Hey, don't blame me!
It's your steering wheel.
The damn thing jerked
right out of my hand!
I don't understand, I had this thing in
for a tune-up yesterday
and they said they'd go over everything.
Yeah, well, you'd better take it back
'cause the damn thing don't work.
The only thing that does work
is this lousy horn.
Aw, go to hell! I'm not honking at you!
Jesus Christ.
Hey, Scotty,
what's this place like anyway?
Well, the guy that's renting it
says it's an old place...
a little run down,
but it's right up in the mountains.
And the best part is we get it so cheap.
Yeah, why are we getting it so cheap?
Well, I don't know.
Might be in real bad shape.
You mean, nobody's seen this place yet?
Well, not yet.
- Well, it might not be that bad.
- No.
- Actually, it might be kinda nice.
- Yeah.
It's probably a real pit.
Hey, I think this is where we get off.
This is the bridge
we're gonna cross?
Jesus Christ, the whole thing's
falling apart on us!
Don't let the noise fool you, girls.
This thing is solid as a rock.
It's supposed to be one of these on here.
- Come on. Hey! Hey!
- Hey!
Hey.
Join us.
Join us...
Dead bodies in the cellar.
- Dead bodies in the cellar.
- Will you stop it?
I would like very much to make
a toast here for all this evening.
- Yeah.
- That sounds all right.
Uh, as a Greek friend of mine once said...
he said, "I..."
No, okay, okay, okay.
"Nis, nis...
tu... tu... tu-tar-im."
- Which means?
- "Party down." Yeah!
What is this?
Whatever it is, it's still down there.
I don't like cellars.
Let's just close it up.
It's probably just some animal.
An animal? An animal?!
That is the stupidest thing
I ever heard of.
Jesus Christ.
Well, there's something down there.
Well, maybe it is just some animal.
Yeah, you're probably right.
It's probably just some animal.
Here, Cheryl. Why don't you go down
and check to make sure?
Scotty, I'm not going down there!
Okay okay, you cowards. I'll go.
Be careful.
Back in a minute.
Hey... hey, Scotty, you find anything?
Scotty?
Scotty!
Scott!
He's just kidding around.
- Isn't he?
- Scotty!
Scott! Linda, get me a flashlight.
Well, that's the only one we brought up.
Then get the lantern.
Scotty?
Hey, come here.
I want to show you something.
Look at all this stuff.
I bet this still shoots.
Probably does.
Oh! God!
Oh, God.
Look at this.
This kind of looks
like your old girlfriend.
Come on,
let's take this stuff upstairs.
I'll grab the recorder
and you get everything else.
Yeah, okay.
This guy was
a real turd, you know?
Everybody hated him.
Like you kind of, right?
Yeah, just like me.
I'm gonna break your face.
Also, he was into this Western stuff.
He makes all these little models...
Okay, shh. Listen to this.
This is the tape I found downstairs.
It has been a number of years
since I began excavating the ruins
of Ca'n Dar with a group of my colleagues.
Now my wife and I have
retreated to a small cabin
in the solitude of these mountains.
Here I continued my research undisturbed
by the myriad distractions
of modern civilization
and far from the groves of academe.
I believe I have made a significant find
in the Ca'n Darian ruins:
A volume of ancient Sumerian
burial practices
and funerary incantations.
It is entitled Naturan Demanto.
Roughly translated... "Book of the Dead."
The book is bound in human flesh
and inked in human blood.
It deals with demons, demon resurrection,
and those forces which roam the forest
and dark bowers of man's domain.
The first few pages warn that
these enduring creatures may lie dormant,
but are never truly dead.
They may be recalled to active life
through the incantations
presented in this book.
It is through recitation of these passages
that the demons are given license
to possess the living.
Hey, what'd you do that for?
It was just getting good.
I just don't wanna
hear it anymore, that's all.
Scott, come on.
Leave her alone, man.
Hey, come on. I just wanna hear
the rest of it.
No big deal.
Tantir-ah-mis-trobeen-ha-zar-ta.
Tantir-manov-
mansis-hazen-sober.
Saman-ta-roza-dûr-hiz-hikar-
dan-derodza.
Kanda.
Shut it off.
Kanda!
Shut it off!
Oh, my God!
Cheryl.
- Where are you going?
- I can't believe this.
Scott, you knew not to play that.
I mean, come on,
you knew it was upsetting her.
You just don't know when
you're taking something too far.
Hey, don't give me that.
You were playing it, too.
You could have shut it off.
I mean, big deal! She's nuts.
I mean, it's just a joke. Come on.
Jesus Christ, she acts like she's
three years old or something.
Listen, why don't we stay up for a while
and listen to the storm?
All right, yeah.
Let me check on Cheryl first
to make sure she's okay.
Okay.
Oh! Stealing from the blind, huh?
It's for you.
Ash, how sweet of you.
- Would you put it on?
- Oh, sure.
I was gonna give it to you
before we came up here,
but things got so hectic.
This is really the first chance
we've had to be alone.
Take a look.
Oh, Ash, it's beautiful.
I really love it. I'll never take it off.
Join us...
Is anybody out there?
I know someone's out there.
I heard you. I heard you in the cellar.
Join us.
Help!
Ashley!
The keys.
Help!
- What the hell happened to you?
- Yeah, what's the matter with you?
Did something in the woods
do this to you?
No, it was the woods themselves.
They're alive, Ashley.
The trees, they're alive!
Ash, why don't I take her
in the back room so she can lie down?
I'm not lying down!
I wanna get out of here!
I wanna leave this place right now.
- Right now, Ashley.
- Wait a minute.
I sure as hell am not leaving
any place tonight.
- Cheryl.
Cheryl, there's nothing out there.
Trees do not attack people.
Ashley, will you drive me
into town or not?
What, right now?
Yeah. Look, sure, sure,
I'll take you into town,
- but just listen to what you're saying.
- I don't care how it sounds.
I wanna get out of this place right now.
Okay, you can stay
somewhere in town tonight.
Come on, come on, come on.
I know it's not gonna start.
It's not gonna let us leave.
Why are you stopping?
Wait here a minute.
Do you see something?
Where you going?!
Ashley?
- It's not gonna let us go!
- What?
It's not gonna let us go! I told you!
I told you, it's not gonna let us go!
Why won't you listen to me?
I know now that my wife
has become host to a Ca'n Darian demon.
I fear that the only way to stop those
possessed by the spirits of the book
is through the act
of bodily dismemberment.
I would leave now to avoid this horror,
but for myself I...
I have seen the dark shadows
moving in the woods,
and I have no doubt that whatever
I have resurrected through this book
is sure to come calling for me.
Okay, let me think. Um... It's a seven.
- What suit?
- Um... diamonds.
No, no, no, wait. Uh, hearts.
Oh my God. Seven of hearts, you're right.
Hey, Ash, I guessed the card right.
Yeah, truly amazing, Linda.
I don't know, I don't know,
but I think it's really some sort
of extra sense or something.
- You know, like ESP?
- Okay, try this.
- Okay, um... it's a seven.
- I don't believe it.
Of spades... queen of spades.
Four of hearts,
eight of spades,
two of spades, jack of diamonds,
jack of clubs.
Why have you
disturbed our sleep,
awakened us from our ancient slumber?
You will die like the others before you!
One by one, we will take you.
What happened to her?
Cheryl?
Did you see her eyes?
Ash, I'm scared. What's wrong with her?
Cheryl, stop it!
Join us. Join us...
Ash, I think we ought to get out of here.
Yeah.
We still have a few more hours
before morning.
I don't think I can wait that long.
You have to. We all have to.
And then in the morning,
we'll get in the car
and we'll take the bridge.
And...
Why does she keep making
those horrible noises?
I don't know!
What about her eyes?
For God's sake,
what happened to her eyes?!
Everything's gonna be all right.
Scotty, I... I think
there's something out there.
Go to bed and get some sleep, okay?
Shelly?
No! Don't burn her! Get her out!
No!
Thank you.
I don't know what I would have done
if I had remained on those hot coals,
burning my pretty flesh.
You have pretty skin.
Give it to us!
Join us! Join us!
Join us!
No, no, no!
Hit her.
Hit her!
Hit it!
Let go! No, no!
You love her! No!
No, you love her! Don't do it!
Scott?
Yeah?
What is... what are we gonna do?
We're gonna bury her.
You can't bury Shelly.
- She's a... she's a friend of ours.
- Ash, she's dead.
Shelly's dead.
We gotta bury her now.
Linda's still sleeping.
- I think once her leg's...
- I'm getting out of here.
Scott, we can't take Linda anywhere
with her leg like that.
We don't even know if there is
any other way back besides the bridge.
Well, maybe there's a hiking trail,
or an old road,
or some other way around the cliff.
I mean, there's gotta be another way
besides the bridge.
Listen to me.
Linda cannot walk with her leg like that.
She can't even stand up.
Well, then we'll leave her here
until we can send somebody back.
What are you, crazy?
- Scott...
- Look, I'm gettin' out!
I don't care what happens to her.
She's your girlfriend.
You take care of her.
I'm getting the hell
out of here right now.
Soon all of you will be like me
and then we will lock you up
in the cellar!
My God, Ash!
Ash.
- Oh my God.
- Help me.
Yes, help me. Yes.
Did you fall, or what?
Scotty, you're gonna be okay.
You're gonna be just fine, you'll see.
Ash, it's not gonna let us leave.
Cheryl... Cheryl was right.
- We're all gonna die here.
- No, we're not gonna die.
We're all gonna die, all of us.
No, we're not gonna die.
We're not gonna die!
We're gonna get outta here!
Now listen to me, Scotty.
Is there a way around the bridge?
Scotty!
Listen to me, please! For God's sake!
Scott!
- Come on.
- Ash...
Ash, I don't wanna die.
You're not gonna leave me,
are you, Ash?
- Are you?
- "I don't wanna die.
You're not gonna
leave me here, are you?
Are you, Ash?"
Scotty, now come on!
Listen to me, for God's sake!
Is there a way around the bridge?!
There's a way... the trail.
But the trees, Ash... they know.
Don't you see, Ash? They're alive.
Shut up! Shut up, Linda!
Shut up!
Kill her. Kill her!
Kill her if you can, lover boy!
God forgive me, Linda.
Oh, Ash... help me, please!
Ash?
Help me, please, Ash.
Oh, Ash, please don't let them
take me away again.
- Please.
- No, I won't.
- I won't, I promise.
Ashley. Ashley, help me.
Let me out of here.
Ashley? Ash, help me.
I'm... I'm all right now.
I'm all right now, Ashley.
I'm all right.
Unlock this chain and let me out.
Cheryl?
I'm all right now, Ashley.
Come unlock the chain and let me out!
I'm all right now.
It's your sister Cheryl.
Oh, you bastards!
Why are you torturing me like this?
Why?!
Shut up.
Useless. Useless.
In time we'll come for him,
and then we'll come for you.
Here. Here.
Now the sun will be up
in an hour or so,
and we can all get out of here together...
you, me, Linda, Shelly.
No, not Shelly. She...
We'll all be going home together.
Wouldn't you like to be going home?
I bet you'd like that, wouldn't you?
Scott?
Join us. Join us.
Oh, Linda.
Come to me.
Come on, get off.
- Oh, God.
- Help, Ashley. Ashley!
The door.
The back door.
Shells... where did I see
that box of shells?
We're gonna get you.
- We're gonna get you.
- Shut up, Linda.
- We're all gonna die.
- Shut up!
- All of us!
- Shut up.
- Ash, how sweet of you.
- God forgive me, Linda.
...through the act
of bodily dismemberment.
- Hit her.
- I really love it.
- I'll never take it off.
Hit it.
No!
Oh, God...
There it is!
Come on, come on.
Why are you torturing me like this?
It's nothing, man.
Linda.
Join us! Ashley, join us!
Must die.
No.
No, no, no! Oh, God!
Join us.
Join us...